Some things are worth fighting for.
The Keeping Room is a western, drama film directed by Daniel Barber.
In this radically reimagined American Western set towards the end of the Civil War, Southerner Augusta
encounters two renegade, drunken soldiers who are on a mission of pillage and violence.
After escaping an attempted assault, Augusta races back to the isolated farmhouse
that she shares with her sister Louise and their female slave Mad.
When the pair of soldiers track Augusta down intent on exacting revenge, the trio of women are forced to take up arms to fend off their assailants,
finding ways to resourcefully defend their home––and themselves––as the escalating attacks become more unpredictable and relentless.
Louise, played by Hailee Steinfeld.
Moses, played by Sam Worthington.
Augusta, played by Brit Marling.
Mad, played by Muna Otaru.
Bill, played by Nicholas Pinnock.
Carriage Driver, played by Charles Jarman.
The Keeping Room is a 2014 American Western film directed
by Daniel Barber and written by Julia Hart.
The film stars Brit Marling, Hailee Steinfeld, Muna Otaru,
Sam Worthington, Amy Nuttall, and Ned Dennehy.
It was screened in the Special Presentations section of the
2014 Toronto International Film Festival.
The film was given a limited release in the United States
on September 25, 2015, by Drafthouse Films.
The film was made available on Netflix US on May 4, 2016.
The film explores themes of rape, mistaken identity,
murder, home invasion, american civil war.
The tone is emotional.